Carrie, what can you do if you want to use one of these more difficult metrics
Carrie 如果要使用某个更难以分析的指标
like a median or
例如中位数、比率或其他无法算出分析方差的指标
ratio or anything where you can't calculate the variants analytically?
你会怎么做？
>> Well, we're going to talk in a minute about specifically computing
我们稍后将专门讨论如何计算经验方差
the variants empirically, but there's actually a broader class of
其实我们还有一大类方法
methods here called non-parametric methods.
就是非参数方法
That means that you have a way to analyze the data without making
也就是说 你无需对分布情况作假设
an assumption about what the distribution Is.
也能分析数据
Now, these methods can be noisier, and they can be more computationally
这些方法更杂乱 需要进行更多计算
intensive, but they can also be very useful.
但也很实用
>> Interesting.
听起来很有意思
So, what's an example of that?
可以举例说明吗？
>> Well, a great simple example is called the sign test.
符号检验就是一个很好的简单例子
Now, let's imagine that we ran our AB experiment for 20 days, and
假设我们要开展一个持续 20 天的 AB 实验
on 15 of those days,
在其中 15 天里
the experiment side had a higher measurement than the control side.
试验组的测量结果均高于对照组
Now, that seems unlikely to have arrived by chance, and
这个结果看起来并非偶尔
what you can do is use what we learned in Lesson One about the binomial
你可以根据第一课中学到的二项分布方法
to actually calculate how likely it is that that occurred,
来计算这个结果的实际发生概率
if there was really no difference between the two sides.
并检查试验组和对照组之间是否真的没有差异
Now, the downside of doing this is that it doesn't help you estimate
这个方法的缺点是 它不能帮助你
the size of the effect.
估计效应的大小
That is, you can't say, you know,
你不能说
I'm confident this is at least 2% change in my metric.
我确信我的指标至少产生了 2% 的变化
The upside is, it's pretty easy to do, and
优点是 它操作简单
you can do it under a lot of different circumstances.
而且适用于很多不同情况
>> Okay, so if you wanted to launch any positive change in your experiment,
如果准备发布在实验中反应良好的一些更改
then you could figure out whether there was one using a sign test.
你就可以使用符号检验来了解是否存在这样的更改
>> Right, and we'll talk a little further about that in Lesson Five.
对的 我们将在第五课详细讲解
>> But, like you mentioned in Lesson One, sometimes you won't want to launch
但是 就像你在第一课中所讲的
unless you meet some threshold, your practical significance level.
有时候你要在达到某个阈值时才发布更改 也就是达到实际显著性水平
So, what then?
这时候应该怎么办？
>> Right. Well,
是的
later in the lesson we're going to talk about how to actually compute
我们将在本节课的后面部分讨论如何根据样本数据
the variance empirically, from the sample data.
计算经验方差
Once you've done that, you have two choices.
得出经验方差后 你就有两种选择
First, if you look at your summary statistic distribution, and
首先 如果你观察总体统计分布
it's pretty nice and normal, you can do what we've done for
当发现它很标准 呈正态分布时
more normally-distributed metrics and use a normal conference interval just
那你就可以像处理正态分布指标一样
with the variants you estimated empirically.
根据方差的经验估计来计算正态分布的置信区间
If your data's a little funnier than that, or
如果你的数据不太标准
if you want to be really robust, you can actually go ahead and
或者如果你想要进行更严谨的分析
compute a non-parametric conference interval.
那就可以选择计算非参数置信区间
It's pretty easy to do, and go ahead in that way.
它其实很简单 你尽可以放手计算